

### **Contact**

- c<sup>2</sup> +49 (0)173 6540032
- im www.linkedin.com/in/ritva-maijaschmitt-0a6369210/
- ® www.behance.net/msschmitt1
  Portfolio website link

### **UX Skills**

User Research
Personas
Usability Testing
Information Architecture
Wireframing & Prototyping
Basic coding skills (HTML, CSS, JS)

#### **Tools**

Adobe XD | Figma | Sketch App Git Hub | Zeplin Microsoft Office Various Teaching Apps

#### **Further Skills**

Leading workshops
Product presentation
Problem-solving
Strategic planning
Analytical Thinking

#### **Education**

UX Design Certificate

CareerFoundry

4/2020 - 5/2021

400+ hours of project-based

UX Design study and practice

2. State Examination Teaching *ZfSL Engelskirchen* 5/2015 - 11/2016

1. State Examination Teaching (Equiv. B.A. & M.A.)

Philipps-University of

Marburg

10/2010-4/2015



Paderborn | Germany | Open to Relocating

### **Profile**

UX/UI designer with a background in education and teaching Gender & Diversity workshops. Experiences in user-centred planning, communicating with different stakeholders; especially in presentation settings, interviews, or collaborative environments.

settings, interviews, or collaborative environments. Skilled in analysing user needs and optimising work processes to reach set goals.

### **Project**

# Freelance UX Designer Lot 1, Berlin

02/2021 - Present

UX Design consultant for a modern-art auction house startup. Led a 3-day workshop to initiate UX research and ideation processes leading up to personas, user flows and low-fidelity wireframes. Designing further wireframes and prototypes. Supporting startup during hand-off to developers.

### Experience

# Teacher Trainer "Gender & Diversity" 07/2019 - Present District Government Detmold

Conducted bi-annual workshops to professionalise teaching staff in gender-related conflicts at school. Mentored schools that decide to tackle gender as part of their school development strategies.

## CAS Coordinator for the IB DP

05/2018 - Present

### Gymnasium Schloss Neuhaus

Improved the programme's efficiency by initiating an introductory workshop to the course to enhance student understanding. Supervised 15+ students with their individual projects, offering process recommendations.

Increased accountability by scheduling regular meetings and progress interviews to assess problems and find solutions.

# Teacher (ESL | Politics & Economics (bilingual) | PE | GFL)

Schloss Neuhaus Grammar School Landrat-Lucas Grammar School 02/2017 - Present

Landrat-Lucas Grammar School 11/2016 - 01/2017 Planned individualised short-, medium- and long-term curricula for each learning group.

Implemented frequent tests to assess individual learning processes.

Established regular qualitative and quantitative research (surveys, interviews) to assess students' needs.